Last year the smoking tire went on the
bull run live rally in the
2010 Ford SBT Raptor. I liked it so
much. I bought one. Here it is.
We're going
back to bull run this year of course
we'll help from our friends at Black
Magic and we're so serious about it. We
got two Valentine one radar detectors.
Oh yeah. So we're all set up and the
reason we got two is because
we're going to
be going a little bit faster. We got a
2011 Shelby GT500. The 550 horsepower
all -luminum V8. We are going to be
right in the action bringing you guys
a
video every single day live from the
bull run rally July 9th to 16th and
the
only place to watch it is on
blackmagicshine .com or right here on
the smoking
tire.