Oh yeah.
Every week I get emails from you guys asking about cheap cars.
Now whether it's a thousand dollars, five thousand dollars, whatever it is, you're always
asking me, where can I get a good car for cheap?
Today we're going to talk about one of those places.
Now we've got this ridiculously pimping El Dorado right here.
And we've got these guys.
This is Chris and George.
Come on over guys.
Good to see you.
Thank you for letting me try out your Cadillac.
These guys are from Cars4Gran.com.
Now tell me about what is Cars4Gran.com other than the very obvious name.
It's the very obvious man.
We founded it in 2007.
Just kind of on a lark.
Just looking at, I mean I'm into old cars.
We're just kind of cruising around eBay and Craigslist and looking at cars and thinking
it would be cool if we had one place where we could kind of gather all those listings.
So we started up Cars4Gran and pulled listings from eBay and Craigslist and Cars.com and
all over the internet.
And then we also set up a free classified service so people can post Cars4FREE and this
is kind of taking off on us.
Has it done well if you guys managed to get a lot of people buying cheap cars or what?
Totally man.
We sell about ten cars a day.
Do you really?
Yeah.
All for under a grand.
All for a grand or under.
Any good feedback from people?
Are they actually buying usable functional cars?
All the time.
We were getting emails from people saying how they couldn't get to work and they needed
a cheap car.
They looked at us up and they found a cheap car to use for work.
Tell me about this L-Doh because this thing is actually quite pimps.
So we found this thing in a garage or in like a guy's barn in Thompson Illinois which is
this tiny little town about 150 miles west of Chicago.
And we kind of cruised around.
We saw a bunch of cars in Chicago that would have probably worked.
They got us down Route 66 when we saw this.
So tell me more about this car because I just drove at about 50 feet and it's awesome.
It's a 1973 Haldrodda.
Yeah.
454.
Well it's got 73 so it's got to make like 160 horsepower out of that right?
Maybe.
I mean I changed spark plugs on which gave a little more horsepower.
I changed the tripper cap which gave a little more juice and she's rocking it about
eight miles a gallon.
That's front wheel drive isn't it?
It's a little torque steer on it for the perfect for the snow.
It's going to be great.
Does the top work?
Yes.
It does.
Is it a power top?
Yes.
And it works.
What does that count?
It's like half a crank.
It starts.
It does now with that new battery.
Oh yeah.
There you go.
It's a bit weird.
That is American muscle right there.
Absolutely.
Front wheel drive is it maybe?
They don't make them like that anymore.
Well I think we should we got to go for ride.
We got to see what a thousand dollars gets you in the world of Cadillac.
Absolutely.
Let's do it.
He thought load is going to really take up the dip.
Flat.
I'm going flat.
Oh it's not bad.
Not bad at all?
No it's not bad at all.
This is fine.
Yeah.
Tranny's good.
It shifts smooth.
It's not fast but it'll it it's not unsafe.
Nope.
It's got four big guys in already.
I've driven brand new economy cars that are slower than that.
Like a Prius.
Like a Prius for example.
And how much is a Prius cost?
That's right.
So you talk about it?
Right.
And you got a thousand.
You got 25 grand for gas.
And that'll take you what about a month to catch up?
Exactly.
Let's do a little Santa Monica cruising and see the dice just makes it too.
Well the dice came with it actually.
Him.
This is what California cruisans all about.
I haven't driven a land yacht convertible since I moved to California.
Where are you from?
New York.
I feel like I've been missing out now.
This is like this is the the move here.
I tell you what anytime you want to come down to San Diego you can ride it around.
Oh for sure.
You got a permanent rental free rent.
Maybe for a track day.
Anytime.
Do this car.
It goes just fast enough for California.
You don't need to go faster than 35 in California ever.
The real problem with a car for a thousand dollars though is you're kind of walking on
eggshells with it aren't you?
Well yeah it depends.
We had kind of a specific goal in mind but I mean you know now that we're done with the
goal ship we can go and do brake stands on this thing all day long.
I don't care.
A front wheel drive brake stand in this would be pretty funny.
But since you have to get to San Diego I won't risk breaking your car.
But yeah I know I'm considered like that.
Unless it's a rental car then forget it.
If I was heard you would have any fault.
No no no.
You know I got to say it drives fine.
It really there's nothing about it that's like this is a broken car.
It's just it's a fine car.
It's not perfect but it works.
Dude if you can find works for a thousand bucks.
You know what I mean?
Works is the best you're going to hope for for it.
Works and character I'd say.
It's just set up for Pimpin.
Like it's pre-pimpin.
You don't have to do anything with it.
It's great.
They want to do it in the 70's just to be able to roll off a lot but immediately go Pimpin.
Oh yeah.
It's boring as much man.
This car I mean this car has got to be within a few inches of a suburban's length right.
This thing is massive.
I don't want to say it's longer.
You think it's longer?
Yeah it's a big car.
If anyone there knows the overall length of a 73 L though compared to a suburban let us
know in the comments because I'd like to see a comparison.
It's great.
Cars with character for those of you at home watching.
Cars with character are much better with the ladies than a Ferrari even right?
I mean I'll trade this for a Ferrari if you want to trade.
By comparison actually we've got the ultimate expression of character and shipboxness right
here.
We've got a 78 looks like Aston Martin V8 Vantage Vellante.
Wow look at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
That's a beautiful.
One of the best shapes to come out of England ever that car.
Such a piece of junk but so awesome to look at.
It's beautiful.
Today we're going to take it back to say hey we do all this interior.
Yeah.
You little bodywork does this little dent in the fender.
You want to redo the interior with like picnic basket plaid cloth.
Awesome.
Right?
So the interior would be about 10 times the price of the car.
Absolutely.
What we're going to do in Tijuana probably better say.
Do they have interior shops in Tijuana?
You can't even expect to be the only industry besides cocaine smuggling.
Is that the secret?
Yeah.
Get your interior done in Tijuana?
The bodywork done too.
Now that's interesting.
Yeah paint all that.
You can get all that done done there.
We got a hood.
It's our coat on paint, George.
Thousand.
Thousand for all the bodywork, all the debts, everything, all the rust and the paint.
Wow.
For a thousand bucks.
Oh, so for two Gs you are so golden right there.
Yeah, two Gs do the interior, do the body.
Whoops.
It's this car is...
There's a suburban.
Do you want to go?
Look.
Yeah, this is totally bigger than that thing.
Way bigger than that.
Totally bigger than the suburban.
Maybe it just looks bigger because we're sitting in it.
No, I'm telling you it's bigger.
So if somebody wanted to buy this car off you, is it for sale or not?
I mean, it's not for sale at this point.
I mean, after you go through so much with the car, you just form a bond, man.
I know.
It's more valuable than the money, though.
Yes.
George, thank you guys for sharing your thousand dollar car with me.
This was awesome.
Perfect California car, am I right?
Absolutely.
I kind of want to buy it off you.
I don't know if we can do that one.
I'm really tempted to.
I'm going to have to sleep on that.
You know what?
You'll find me another one for a thousand bucks.
I'll buy it.
We'll do.
I'll tell you what, if you guys have been a fine discremened deal on a car, they're out
there.
Believe me.
Leave a comment.
Let's see how far a thousand dollars or two thousand dollars would go.
That's Chris and George, cars for grand.com.
I'm Matt.
You've been watching The Smoke Entire.
I'll see you guys next week.
This year, Blackmagic sending us on the 2010 Bola and Live rally from July 9th to 16th
New York to Las Vegas.
We're going to be driving the 2011 Shelby GT 500 convertible.
Now ours is going to be red, but it's not out yet.
So you got this beautiful 2010 instead.
Here's your chance to come hang out with us, the Bull Run launch party in New York.
All you do is go to blackmagicshine.com and design your own racing livery using the tools
they give you.
I did it myself.
It's not that hard.
Goldberg is going to choose the winner.
And the best design ends up on our car for Bull Run and Blackmagic is going to pay for
your trip to New York to come hang out with us at the kickoff party.
So go to blackmagicshine.com and be sure to watch all our videos almost live from the Bull Run
rally right here on the Smoking Tire.
It's like Walmart had a sale on here.
It's a Fob Jaina.
I don't know what else to call it.
We can even binge the earth to its will.
This car is impossible to drive slowly.