Welcome to the spine specialist and to our segment.
Nice to know today once again, a quick explanation.
What's the difference between a paresis and a plegia?
Before we get into the difference, let's first define
the term paresis.
Paresis is actually just the Latin term for paralysis.
And in a neurological exam, not all paralysis is the
same.
We actually divide it into five strength levels, which
help us better classify the paralysis and make an
assessment.
This strength grading system is named after janda.
There are five strength grades.
We say five out of five for full muscle strength and
zero out of five when there's basically no movement
left.
Five out of five means the patient has full strength.
Basically, 100% muscle function is present.
With four out of five, the patient can still move
against greater resistance with three out of five
only if the resistance is removed.
Two would be when movement is possible only against
the weight of the limb itself, but can still be performed.
For example, in foot drop, the patient can just barely
lift the foot a little, but there is no resistance
that needs to be overcome.
One out of five means even that is gone and only minimal
muscle strength remains.
And zero out of five would mean not even a contraction.
In other words, complete lack of strength.
Now, the difference compared to plegia describes complete
paralysis, meaning the patient cannot move the affected
body part at all, unlike the previously mentioned
paresis.
With paresis, depending on the degree, you can still
see a bit of movement.
If you have any comments or questions about this,
feel free to reach out.